<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-10-05T14:45:43+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">HappyMothersLand</title><subtitle>Caring, Sharing, and Growing with Your Baby</subtitle><entry><title type="html">2-Month-Old Baby: Milestones and Development</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2-month-old-baby-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2-Month-Old Baby: Milestones and Development" /><published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2-month-old-baby-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2-month-old-baby-development/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="development-of-a-2-month-old-baby">Development of a 2-Month-Old Baby</h1>

<p>Congratulations, you’ve completed the first month with your baby! The second month promises to be more relaxed and experienced. Your baby’s sleep patterns are beginning to form, they’ll become more active, and you might even witness their first smile. Let’s explore what to expect in terms of feeding frequency, sleep routines, and the behavior of your 2-month-old baby, along with their sensory development.</p>

<h2 id="2-month-old-baby-growth-chart">2-Month-Old Baby Growth Chart</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/2-month-chart-1.png" alt="1-Month-Old Baby Sleeping" /></p>

<p>During the second month, your baby will continue to gain weight at a similar rate to the first few weeks, typically around 150 to 200 grams per week. Their cheeks, arms, and legs will start to fill out gradually. While the average weight for a 2-month-old baby is 4-5 kg, remember that each healthy baby may have different growth rates in terms of size and weight. The baby’s height may increase by approximately 1-1.5 cm per month.</p>

<p>The head and brain of your baby continue to develop at the same rate. The head circumference increases by about 1.25 cm per month. It’s normal for the baby’s head to be larger than other body parts during this period, as the head continues to grow faster than other organs. The baby’s soft spot on the skull (fontanel) remains open but starts to harden and close slightly toward the end of the second month and the beginning of the third month.</p>

<h2 id="sensory-development-of-a-2-month-old-baby">Sensory Development of a 2-Month-Old Baby</h2>

<h3 id="vision-at-2-months">Vision at 2 Months</h3>

<p>In the second month, your baby’s vision becomes clearer and more vibrant compared to the previous month. You can now introduce them to pastel colors. Their improved vision means they will show more interest in bright and vivid colors. They will also examine your movements and speech with their eyes, so you might notice them vocalizing as a result. However, these sounds will consist of voiced consonants, as they have not yet mastered using their tongue for speech. This is completely normal, as babies typically start using voiceless consonants between 3 to 5 months of age.</p>

<h3 id="hearing-at-2-months">Hearing at 2 Months</h3>

<p>In the second month, your baby’s hearing becomes stronger than in the previous month. They will likely perceive your voice more clearly. You can even notice them becoming concerned if they don’t hear your voice for an extended period. They can distinguish between high-pitched and low-pitched sounds. For instance, they can differentiate between your voice and their father’s voice. You can gauge their responses by playing the same familiar melodies or reading the same story repeatedly. Since their hearing has improved, they will produce more sounds. Although these sounds will be mainly voiced consonants, there’s nothing to worry about. Babies typically start using voiceless consonants between 3 to 5 months of age.</p>

<h3 id="sense-of-smell-at-2-months">Sense of Smell at 2 Months</h3>

<p>Your baby has been exposed to various scents since birth, such as the smell of breast milk, your perfume, or the aroma of cooked chicken. As long as they don’t show sensitivity to smells, you can introduce them to other scents.</p>

<h3 id="sense-of-taste-at-2-months">Sense of Taste at 2 Months</h3>

<p>At this stage, there’s no need to stimulate your baby’s sense of taste. They can only detect the taste of mother’s milk and bottle milk during this period. As they grow, exploring and tasting everything they find will become their way of researching the world. As long as these objects are not sharp or dangerous, it’s best not to intervene.</p>

<h3 id="sense-of-touch-at-2-months">Sense of Touch at 2 Months</h3>

<p>The sense of touch is one of the most meaningful senses your baby uses to explore the world and understand how they should be touched. Try to understand how your baby prefers to be touched. Many babies enjoy being kissed, cuddled, or having their tummies tickled. There’s nothing better than hands filled with love. Expose your baby to different fabric textures and place them on different surfaces while lying on their stomach. Give them a massage for at least 20 minutes. Babies who receive massages gain weight more quickly and show better development. Infants who are not touched enough may experience growth delays.</p>

<h2 id="mental-development-of-a-2-month-old-baby">Mental Development of a 2-Month-Old Baby</h2>

<p>So far, your baby has been listening to and absorbing the conversations and sounds around them. Although they can’t vocalize their thoughts yet, they started understanding the meanings of words months before they began speaking. So, talk to your baby as much as possible. Look forward to those cooing and babbling sounds, which usually start between the 6th and 8th weeks. Your baby will eventually use their lips more effectively to create clearer sounds. This development in their tongue goes hand in hand with their motor skills.</p>

<h2 id="social-development-of-a-2-month-old-baby">Social Development of a 2-Month-Old Baby</h2>

<p>Your baby will still spend most of their time sleeping. However, a 6-week-old baby can respond to your smiles with smiles in return. Responding positively to their smiles will help them realize that their actions have an effect, thus developing their ability to distinguish themselves from others.</p>

<h3 id="what-can-a-2-month-old-baby-do">What Can a 2-Month-Old Baby Do?</h3>

<ul>
  <li>They can lift their body at a 45-degree angle when placed on their stomach. By the middle of this month, they may even lift their head at a 90-degree angle.</li>
  <li>They start to explore and play with their hands.</li>
  <li>They often engage with their hands and feet.</li>
  <li>When an object is placed in front of them or given to them, they can begin to grasp it. They may attempt to bring small objects to their mouths and shake larger objects.</li>
  <li>They can’t completely control their body movements yet, so it’s important not to leave them unattended on high surfaces.</li>
  <li>They sleep less during the day and more at night.</li>
  <li>They find joy in hearing their own voice and will make sounds frequently.</li>
  <li>They can smile and make joyful cries.</li>
  <li>They understand when they are being paid attention to.</li>
  <li>They enjoy making sounds more than ever.</li>
  <li>They can clearly recognize their mother’s voice.</li>
  <li>They might even squeal with happiness.</li>
  <li>Sucking can help calm them.</li>
  <li>When they cry, especially when you hold them, they can calm down.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="toys-for-a-2-month-old-baby">Toys for a 2-Month-Old Baby</h3>

<p>Since your baby will stay awake for longer periods, they will benefit from simple, safe, and colorful toys that help them improve their hand-eye coordination. Here are some suitable toys:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Rattles: These are great for stimulating your baby’s sense of hearing.</li>
  <li>Mobiles: Hanging mobiles with colorful and contrasting objects can grab your baby’s attention.</li>
  <li>Soft Toys: Soft, plush toys with different textures can be comforting and engaging.</li>
  <li>Play Mats: These have hanging toys that encourage reaching and swatting.</li>
  <li>Mirror Toys: Babies are fascinated by their own reflection.</li>
  <li>Black and White Books: These high-contrast books are visually stimulating for infants.</li>
  <li>Sensory Balls: Soft balls with textures for tactile stimulation.</li>
</ul>

<p>Remember that at this age, your baby will primarily enjoy looking at, listening to, and touching toys rather than actively playing with them. Keep safety in mind when selecting toys, ensuring there are no small parts that could be a choking hazard.</p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>The second month of your baby’s life is a period of rapid development, both physically and mentally. They are becoming more alert, responsive, and interactive. As a parent, continue to provide love, care, and attention to support their growth and well-being. Every baby is unique, so be sure to consult with your pediatrician if you have any specific concerns about your baby’s development.</p>]]></content><author><name>admin</name></author><category term="Baby Development" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Milestones" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Care Tips" /><category term="Infant Development at 2 Month" /><category term="Baby Reflexes at 2 Month" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Growth Chart" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Feeding Schedule" /><category term="Baby's First Month of Life" /><category term="Newborn Sensory Development" /><category term="Cognitive Development in Infants" /><category term="Sleep Patterns of a 2-Month-Old Baby" /><category term="Parenting a 2-Month-Old Baby" /><category term="Baby Developmental Milestones Month by Month" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Health and Nutrition" /><category term="Bonding with Your 2-Month-Old" /><category term="2-Month-Old Baby Sleep Tips" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Development of a 2-Month-Old Baby]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-and-mom-hug-newborn.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-and-mom-hug-newborn.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">1-Month-Old Baby Development: Milestones, Reflexes, and Care</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/1-month-old-baby-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1-Month-Old Baby Development: Milestones, Reflexes, and Care" /><published>2023-10-05T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2023-10-05T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/1-month-old-baby-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/1-month-old-baby-development/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="1-month-old-baby-development-milestones-reflexes-and-care">1 Month Old Baby Development: Milestones, Reflexes, and Care</h1>

<p>After a long pregnancy and the birthing process, you have finally met your precious baby. The time of tracking your pregnancy week by week is over, and now we will explore your baby’s growth, nutrition, movements, emotional development, and cognitive abilities on a monthly basis. Don’t underestimate the changes that can occur in the first month. Be prepared for new discoveries every day. Let’s delve into the development of a 1-month-old baby!</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1-month-chart-1.png" alt="1-Month-Old Baby Sleeping" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>Your baby loses the excess fluid present in their body at birth, which means they might weigh slightly less than their birth weight when they come home. Don’t worry; in 1-month-old babies, weight gain typically increases within 10 days to 2 weeks.</li>
  <li>During the first two weeks, your baby grows rapidly. As they gain weight, their height also increases. At the end of the first month, your baby will have grown approximately 4-5 cm.</li>
  <li>The size of your baby’s head is important because it reflects the growth rate of their brain. In the early months, both the brain and the skull of your baby grow rapidly. While the baby’s head accounts for 20% of their body weight at birth, it will only represent 2% in adulthood. Consult a doctor for information on your baby’s head growth during the first month.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="1-month-old-baby-reflexes">1-Month-Old Baby Reflexes</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Sucking Reflex:</strong> This reflex is a habit acquired by the baby while in the womb. You can observe that when you bring your finger, a bottle, a pacifier, or your breast close to their cheek, they will turn their head and mouth in that direction.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Moro Reflex:</strong> This reflex is observed in the development of a 1-month-old baby. It is an immediate response to a specific stimulus. It often occurs when the baby’s head suddenly changes position or when startled by a loud noise. In response, the baby raises their hands and feet, extends their neck, and may quiver their chin.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Tonic Neck Reflex:</strong> An interesting reflex is the tonic neck reflex. When your baby’s head turns in one direction, the arm on that side straightens, while the other arm bends.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Stepping Reflex:</strong> Another reflex your baby has is the stepping reflex. When you lift your baby under their armpits, they may appear to take steps or walk. This is called the stepping reflex. However, it’s a movement they will forget around 4 months old but will relearn after crawling.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p><strong>Grasp Reflex:</strong> If you bring your finger close to your baby’s hand, they can quickly grasp it and pull it up. However, as with other 1-month-old baby reflexes, this reflex will change and gradually disappear as your baby develops more control, usually around the 3rd or 4th month.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Let’s see when these reflexes begin and end:</strong></p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/1-month-chart-2.png" alt="1-Month-Old Baby Sleeping" /></p>

<p>These reflexes are related to both fine and gross motor skills. If you want to see more details about motor development in children, you can explore “Fine and Gross Motor Development in Children.”</p>

<h2 id="1-month-old-babys-sensory-development">1-Month-Old Baby’s Sensory Development</h2>

<h3 id="vision-at-1-month">Vision at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>You may wonder, “When do babies start to see?” Well, they start seeing almost immediately, but only at short distances!</li>
  <li>In the first month, they have a visual range of only 15 to 30 cm. Don’t worry; this distance won’t prevent them from seeing you while they breastfeed. Allow them to study and recognize you.</li>
  <li>If you’re curious about how a 1-month-old baby sees, it’s worth noting that they see distant objects as blurry, but their vision improves over time.</li>
  <li>Dark-colored objects usually catch their attention. To engage them, introduce dark and brightly colored objects within their line of sight.</li>
  <li>When you bring objects closer to their visual range, they can track them for a short period.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="hearing-at-1-month">Hearing at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Although their visual sense is still developing, 1-month-old babies are sensitive to human voices, especially yours.</li>
  <li>Since they heard your voice the most while in the womb, it’s natural for a 1-month-old baby to recognize you and respond when they hear your voice. Seize this opportunity to comfort them and engage in conversations.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="smell-at-1-month">Smell at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Babies have a well-developed sense of smell at birth and can quickly distinguish the smell of your breast milk.</li>
  <li>Towards the end of this month, you may notice their preference for sweet scents like vanilla or banana, but they may dislike strong odors like alcohol or vinegar.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="taste-at-1-month">Taste at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>It might surprise you, but newborns have more taste buds than you! That’s why your baby might be selective about different tastes, including the warmth of your breast milk or formula.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="touch-at-1-month">Touch at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Your baby’s sense of touch is also well-developed.</li>
  <li>They prefer smooth surfaces and may not like the sensation of different materials simultaneously touching their skin.</li>
  <li>They can also feel pain and may react when touched.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="cognitive-development-at-1-month">Cognitive Development at 1 Month</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Your baby’s brain has been producing approximately 250,000 new brain cells per minute since your pregnancy. By the time they are born, they have created almost all the cells they will use throughout their life.</li>
  <li>However, this is just the beginning. As your baby grows and explores the new world, their brain cells will start forming connections called synapses, laying the foundation for various skills.</li>
  <li>You might think it’s too early to contribute to their brain development, especially in areas like language. However, that’s not the case. Talking to them, even though they can’t respond with words yet, is incredibly valuable. Reading aloud to them is also an excellent way to support language development.</li>
  <li>Your baby has some ways to communicate and express themselves, even if they can’t talk. One of these is crying. Unless there’s an underlying health issue, why does a 1-month-old baby cry? It’s mainly for three reasons: hunger, sleepiness, or discomfort. Responding to their cries by addressing these needs is crucial in building trust and security.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="feeding-a-1-month-old-baby">Feeding a 1-Month-Old Baby</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Your baby is primarily fed with breast milk or formula at this stage. Breastfeeding provides essential nutrients and helps strengthen their immune system.</li>
  <li>Newborns usually feed every 2-3 hours, and it’s essential to feed them on demand. Pay attention to your baby’s cues, such as rooting, sucking on their hands, or crying, which may indicate hunger.</li>
  <li>Feeding should be a relaxed and comfortable experience for both you and your baby. Ensure a comfortable feeding position, and burp your baby gently after each feeding to prevent gas.</li>
  <li>Consult with a healthcare professional or lactation consultant if you have any breastfeeding concerns or issues.</li>
  <li>If you’re using formula, follow the recommended guidelines for preparing and feeding formula milk.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="sleeping-a-1-month-old-baby">Sleeping a 1-Month-Old Baby</h2>

<p><img src="/assets/images/newborn-sleeping.png" alt="1-Month-Old Baby Sleeping" /></p>

<ul>
  <li>Sleep is a crucial aspect of your baby’s development. Newborns sleep a lot, typically 14-17 hours a day. However, their sleep patterns can be quite irregular during the first few months.</li>
  <li>Babies often wake up during the night to feed and have their diapers changed. Make sure their sleep environment is safe and comfortable, with no loose bedding or toys in the crib.</li>
  <li>To help establish a day-night sleep routine, keep the room dark and quiet during nighttime feedings and diaper changes. During the day, allow natural light into their environment.</li>
  <li>Your baby will develop a more consistent sleep schedule as they grow.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="1-month-old-baby-care-tips">1-Month-Old Baby Care Tips</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Skin Care:</strong> Your baby’s skin is delicate and sensitive. Keep it clean and dry. Use a mild, fragrance-free baby soap and moisturizer if necessary.</li>
  <li><strong>Umbilical Cord Care:</strong> If the umbilical cord stump is still attached, keep it clean and dry. Avoid submerging your baby in water until it falls off.</li>
  <li><strong>Diapering:</strong> Change your baby’s diaper regularly to prevent diaper rash. Clean the diaper area gently with each change and use a diaper cream if needed.</li>
  <li><strong>Safety:</strong> Ensure your baby’s safety by babyproofing your home. Keep small objects, cords, and hazardous substances out of reach.</li>
  <li><strong>Immunizations:</strong> Stay on schedule with your baby’s immunizations as recommended by your healthcare provider.</li>
</ul>

<p>As your baby grows, you’ll witness numerous changes and milestones. Each month will bring new surprises and joys as you watch your baby’s development unfold. Embrace this incredible journey and cherish every moment with your 1-month-old baby.</p>]]></content><author><name>admin</name></author><category term="Baby Development" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Milestones" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Care Tips" /><category term="Infant Development at 1 Month" /><category term="Baby Reflexes at 1 Month" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Growth Chart" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Feeding Schedule" /><category term="Baby's First Month of Life" /><category term="Newborn Sensory Development" /><category term="Cognitive Development in Infants" /><category term="Sleep Patterns of a 1-Month-Old Baby" /><category term="Parenting a 1-Month-Old Baby" /><category term="Baby Developmental Milestones Month by Month" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Health and Nutrition" /><category term="Bonding with Your 1-Month-Old" /><category term="1-Month-Old Baby Sleep Tips" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[1 Month Old Baby Development: Milestones, Reflexes, and Care]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-and-mom-hug-newborn.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/baby-and-mom-hug-newborn.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2019-02-04T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-04T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll/"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>To add new posts, simply add a file in the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory that follows the convention <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext</code> and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/demo1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/demo1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor" /><published>2019-02-03T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-03T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/powerful-things-markdown-editor/"><![CDATA[<p>There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!</p>

<p>As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.</p>

<h2 id="special-formatting">Special formatting</h2>

<p>As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:</p>

<ul>
  <li><del>strike through</del></li>
  <li>==highlight==</li>
  <li>*escaped characters*</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="writing-code-blocks">Writing code blocks</h2>

<p>There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">like this</code>. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8.jpg" alt="walking" /></p>

<h2 id="reference-lists">Reference lists</h2>

<p>The quick brown jumped over the lazy.</p>

<p>Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.</p>

<h2 id="full-html">Full HTML</h2>

<p>Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:</p>

<p><iframe style="width:100%;" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]></content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="summer" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor. If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1528784351875-d797d86873a1?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=750&amp;q=80" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1528784351875-d797d86873a1?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;auto=format&amp;fit=crop&amp;w=750&amp;q=80" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format" /><published>2019-02-02T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-02T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/first-mass-produced/"><![CDATA[<p>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.</p>

<p>An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.</p>

<p>As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.</p>

<p>To deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.</p>

<p>An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.</p>

<p>As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.</p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="tutorial" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/17.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/17.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/education/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Education must also train one for quick, resolute and effective thinking." /><published>2019-02-01T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-02-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/education</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/"><![CDATA[<p>There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor</p>

<p>If you’ve gotten pretty comfortable with writing in Markdown, then you may enjoy some more advanced tips about the types of things you can do with Markdown!</p>

<p>As with the last post about the editor, you’ll want to be actually editing this post as you read it so that you can see all the Markdown code we’re using.</p>

<h2 id="special-formatting">Special formatting</h2>

<p>As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:</p>

<ul>
  <li><del>strike through</del></li>
  <li>==highlight==</li>
  <li>*escaped characters*</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="writing-code-blocks">Writing code blocks</h2>

<p>There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">like this</code>. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:</p>

<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using Rouge.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/8.jpg" alt="walking" /></p>

<h2 id="reference-lists">Reference lists</h2>

<p>The quick brown jumped over the lazy.</p>

<p>Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.</p>

<h2 id="full-html">Full HTML</h2>

<p>Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you’re never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Markdown editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here’s a standard YouTube embed code as an example:</p>

<p><iframe style="width:100%;" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;showinfo=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are lots of powerful things you can do with the Markdown editor]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/3.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/3.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Accumulated experience of social living</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accumulated experience of social living" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/acumulated-experience/"><![CDATA[<p>The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.</p>

<p>As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original - which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother - is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.</p>

<p>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.</p>

<p>An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.</p>
</blockquote>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/15.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/15.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">About Bundler</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about-bundler/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About Bundler" /><published>2019-01-29T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-01-29T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about-bundler</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about-bundler/"><![CDATA[<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gem install bundler</code> installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundler</code> is a gem that manages other Ruby gems. It makes sure your gems and gem versions are compatible, and that you have all necessary dependencies each gem requires.</p>

<p>The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Gemfile</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Gemfile.lock</code> files inform <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Bundler</code> about the gem requirements in your site. If your site doesn’t have these Gemfiles, you can omit <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec</code> and just <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">run jekyll serve</code>.</p>

<p>When you run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code>, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Bundler</code> uses the gems and versions as specified in <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Gemfile.lock</code> to ensure your Jekyll site builds with no compatibility or dependency conflicts.</p>

<p>For more information about how to use <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Bundler</code> in your Jekyll project, this tutorial should provide answers to the most common questions and explain how to get up and running quickly.</p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[gem install bundler installs the bundler gem through RubyGems. You only need to install it once - not every time you create a new Jekyll project. Here are some additional details:]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We all wait for summer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We all wait for summer" /><published>2019-01-28T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-01-28T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer/"><![CDATA[<p>This is changed. As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that <a href="#">education should equip</a> them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.</p>

<p>It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.</p>]]></content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is changed. As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tree of Codes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tree-of-codes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tree of Codes" /><published>2019-01-27T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2019-01-27T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tree-of-codes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tree-of-codes/"><![CDATA[<p>The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.</p>

<p>As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.</p>

<p>The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.</p>]]></content><author><name>sal</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>